[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e2", "question": "What fruit comes in Redhaven and Harmony variety?", "answer": "Peaches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e0", "question": "Who took Oliver Twist into his home even though he had been accused of picking his pockets?", "answer": "Mr. Brownlow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b629", "question": "The \"Remington #2\" is what?", "answer": "A typewritter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdf", "question": "Who invented the radio alarm clock?", "answer": "James F. Reynolds", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974b", "question": "What pop star originally began her career as Christian singer \"Katherine Hudson\"?", "answer": "Katy Perry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f9", "question": "Which UK band had a 1974 hit with \"Billy Don't Be A Hero\"?", "answer": "Paper Lace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be57d0b5415ba52ed6f0aa5", "question": "In which children\u2019s series is the villain named Count Olaf?", "answer": "A Series of Unfortunate Events", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a552683e1c6f9840ba3195", "question": "Where was the Armistice of 11 November 1918 signed?", "answer": "Compiegne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25a53b63e5727cf5a4852", "question": "Who sang the songs \"Bump n' Grind\" and \"She's Got That Vibe\"?", "answer": "R Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe698e720565ad31a57c73d", "question": "Which coffee innovation was developed by German housewife Melitta Bentz?", "answer": "Coffee filter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59029ef7cad1ec93f27df75a", "question": "Above 5,000 ft, coffee beans tend to develop a high level of what?", "answer": "Acidity", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f5", "question": "What TV mother has presided over the longest-running American sitcom ever?", "answer": "Marge Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac3", "question": "Joe Cool is an alter ego of which comic strip character?", "answer": "Snoopy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dce", "question": "What two Rocky III costars won the final match of the very first WrestleMania?", "answer": "Mr. T and Hulk Hogan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb4997e83c707845b211a", "question": "What color is eigengrau?", "answer": "Dark gray", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59774255284458f1d785441f", "question": "Who played Secret Service Agent James West in The 1966-1968 television series \"The Wild, Wild, West\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a206", "question": "What comedy team's films included \"Hollywood or Bust\" and \"Living It Up\"?", "answer": "Dean Martin and Jerry Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597ddba577980686f722d177", "question": "What year was the first patent for a pencil sharpener applied for?", "answer": "1828", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c071", "question": "What is the name of the kneeling cushions in churches?", "answer": "Hassock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c19b", "question": "Which British driver was Formula One World Champion in 1996?", "answer": "Damon Hill", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbd", "question": "Where might you drink Retsina wine?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb47c65ff7d326b622a89", "question": "What is Nelophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Glass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb7", "question": "Who wrote the 1971 novel \"The Exorcist\"?", "answer": "William Peter Blatty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e3", "question": "Which band recorded the live album titled \"Strangers in the Night\"?", "answer": "UFO", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f700ea9e54d890926f6d4", "question": "South America\u2019s Atacama Desert holds what distinction?", "answer": "Driest non-polar desert -- Although it is home to about one million people, it records less than 1 mm of rain every year.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b458", "question": "Who is typically referred to as \"The Father of History\"?", "answer": "Herodotus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523c9d736d4be723796b39", "question": "What are Canada\u2019s two official sports?", "answer": "Ice hockey and lacrosse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a63842ebb971c1417fb9a", "question": "Which band released the song \"Proud Mary\" in 1969?", "answer": "Creedence Clearwater Revival", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd0a9ec223966ae8f88ba", "question": "In the movie \"The Martian\", where were the Mars exterior scenes shot?", "answer": "Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2eca58d116dab4aecb42", "question": "What is the name of the inventor in the 1989 film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\"?", "answer": "Wayne Szalinski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6fc", "question": "What dermatological problem do you most likely have if you have over secreting sebaceous glands?", "answer": "Acne", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff145edb0ee8c595b6d39bd", "question": "What is Dr. Frankenstein's first name?", "answer": "Victor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3a9cff048f679a45ab2c", "question": "What color has the longest wavelength in the visible spectrum?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b11", "question": "Which of the Seven Dwarfs wears glasses?", "answer": "Doc", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ef", "question": "In The Simpsons, which immigrant in Springfield actually got deported once?", "answer": "Groundskeeper Willie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a419", "question": "What Scottish landmark borders on Fort Augustus?", "answer": "Loch Ness", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c798", "question": "Which scientist is credited with being the first one to isolate DNA material in 1869?", "answer": "Friedrich Miescher", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac8", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Montana?", "answer": "Helena", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c753fbde8045e48466c1", "question": "What is the scientific name of the plant used to make liquorice?", "answer": "Glycyrrhiza glabra, the plant used to make liquorice, is native to Europe and Asia.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbb", "question": "Which sea is located between Australia and New Zealand?", "answer": "Tasman Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a173", "question": "Who created the characters Wallace and Gromit?", "answer": "Nick Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a28220565ad31a57c7ad", "question": "What city was home to the first movie theater in the United States?", "answer": "Pittsburgh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6eb", "question": "Which US state is located between California and Utah?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6da", "question": "The Bering Strait separates Russia from which US state?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a6", "question": "Who originally designed the Washington Monument?", "answer": "Robert Mills", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d0", "question": "Who directed the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Charles Walters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83b", "question": "How many horizontal rows of stars are there on the U.S. flag?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf5", "question": "What river is the setting for the novel \"The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn\"?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fa", "question": "What metal do you get from Hematite?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f1cb01dd7bf43be5e808", "question": "Which Crayola color did consumers vote to save from retirement in 2003?", "answer": "Burnt sienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6f18a9e54d890926f6ce", "question": "What color are gondolas required to be painted in Venice?", "answer": "Black -- A 17th century doge's decree dictated that all gondolas must be painted with six coats of black paint.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e8c", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Molly in \"Home Alone 3\"?", "answer": "Scarlett Johansson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071d823745b36be73039d9", "question": "What year did the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union start?", "answer": "1955", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c8a6d690aac110e4167081", "question": "How many milliliters is a teaspoon?", "answer": "5 mL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa45", "question": "What US state is known as \"The Magnolia State\"?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8c", "question": "What ingredient appears alongside potatoes in the Indian dish aloo gobi?", "answer": "Cauliflower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946b", "question": "What movie earned Katharine Hepburn her last Oscar?", "answer": "On Golden Pond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d7", "question": "What extinct subspecies of zebra had stripes in front but a plain brown hindquarters?", "answer": "The quagga", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc0706ce05a3942286f08", "question": "Who starred as Rudy Baylor in the 1997 film \"Rainmaker\"?", "answer": "Matt Damon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904995ecf93664eb1048690", "question": "What is the capital of Antigua and Barbuda?", "answer": "St. John's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e1", "question": "The islands called Islas Malvinas by the Argentinians are referred to by what name by the British?", "answer": "The Falklands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3db", "question": "What was the four letter name of Thailand before 1949?", "answer": "Siam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be87", "question": "What type of a tree killed Albert Camus?", "answer": "Plane tree", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa8", "question": "At which famous American battle was General Custer defeated by Sitting Bull?", "answer": "Little Bighorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af9", "question": "Which character killed Aslan?", "answer": "The White Witch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13c", "question": "In what year did Joseph Smith first organize the Mormon Church?", "answer": "1830", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d36", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Reading Gaol\"?", "answer": "Oscar Wilde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c028d3fea32143fcb1d3b57", "question": "Who created the \"Dragonriders Of Pern\" series?", "answer": "Anne McCaffrey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febaeee7e83c707845b20f9", "question": "What gives eyes their color?", "answer": "Melanin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe738d1eec85e375820b268", "question": "In which country do people traditionally eat at KFC for Christmas?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d0776d870e6f05ba600863", "question": "What was astronaut Edwin Eugene Aldrin Jr.'s nickname?", "answer": "Buzz", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd69fb66c0f9723ab15cb2e", "question": "Benazir Bhutto was the first female prime minister of which country?", "answer": "Pakistan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a996", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Lassen Peak\"?", "answer": "The United States", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a2", "question": "How long do rodeo bull and bronco riders have to stay on their mounts for?", "answer": "8 seconds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad36", "question": "When first founded by Benjamin Franklin, what was the job of the \"bucket brigade\"?", "answer": "To put out fires", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969b", "question": "What does Martin Blank do for a living in the 1997 movie \"Grosse Point Blank\"?", "answer": "He is a hitman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c7c49076251badbead5", "question": "Which newspaper incorrectly reported Thomas E. Dewey defeated Harry S. Truman in the 1948 U.S. Presidential Election?", "answer": "Chicago Daily Tribune -- Now known as Chicago Tribune, it had once referred to Truman as a \"nincompoop\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a852", "question": "Approximately, how many feet above the sea level is Machi Picchu located at?", "answer": "8,000", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0a", "question": "Are pumpkins fruits or vegetables?", "answer": "Fruits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb83", "question": "What citrus beverage has used the ad slogan \"Open a Bottle of Sunshine\"?", "answer": "Sunny Delight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c5", "question": "What was the family name of the aliens on the TV show \"3rd Rock from the Sun\"?", "answer": "The Solomons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ff", "question": "In the movie \"Ghost\", what was Sam Wheat's profession?", "answer": "A banker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a5", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e56efe83fe1f2a824bbe", "question": "In which country was Buddha born?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f4", "question": "What actor played the role of Korben Dallas in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Bruce Willis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd6", "question": "Who played the title character in the film \"The Omega Man\"?", "answer": "Charlton Heston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea788fff048f679a45abdb", "question": "What is a \"Haricot Vert\"?", "answer": "A tender string bean", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd8", "question": "What TV show did \"Young Americans\" spin off from?", "answer": "Dawson's Creek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b79b", "question": "What type of fruit juice is used to make the drink \"Fuzzy Navel\"?", "answer": "Orange Juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133990a", "question": "What band, formed in 1977, was fronted by singer/guitarist Mark Knopfler?", "answer": "Dire Straits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae98", "question": "Who was US president when the stock market crashed in 1929?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00b", "question": "What duo explored the Pacific Northwest during the early 1800s?", "answer": "Lewis and Clark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a363", "question": "What is the capital of Bulgaria?", "answer": "Sofia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb88", "question": "What gun manufacturer's first names were Horace and Daniel?", "answer": "Smith & Wesson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d1", "question": "What is the abbreviation for trinitrotoluene?", "answer": "TNT", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7eb8eb24f84e0b9f9ffde", "question": "What state borders Alabama to the north?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937ed2708d98002fdd633c6", "question": "The 1976 Summer Olympics were held in which city?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b13ce662d71a53650fcf", "question": "What is the name of the train station that services Hogwarts School?", "answer": "Hogsmeade Station", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be5806d5415ba52ed6f0ab4", "question": "Saint Stephen's Day is better known as what?", "answer": "Boxing day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339477", "question": "Who played the role of David Dunn in the movie \"Unbreakable\"?", "answer": "Bruce Willis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb7", "question": "What made-up expletive is \"Battlestar Galactica's\" dirty word of choice?", "answer": "Frak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9d9", "question": "Which African country had its capital transferred to Abuja?", "answer": "Nigeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1d", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Douglas?", "answer": "Ashanti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b13", "question": "Who did Lionel Richie duet with on the 1981 #1 smash \"Endless Love\"?", "answer": "Diana Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93ac66bd93ce3a4e5f69b", "question": "What is the scientific study of animal biology?", "answer": "Zoology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f43", "question": "Who created the character of Fozzie Bear?", "answer": "Jim Henson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66a08a5bfecdd737e087f", "question": "What was the first company to air a legal TV commercial?", "answer": "Bulova watch company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb63", "question": "In what European country is the headquarters for the World Health Organization?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7db", "question": "What was the first European country to ban smoking in bars?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1ce1a7bd84c0ea43ad433", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Computer Power and Human Reason\"?", "answer": "Joseph Weizenbaum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338999", "question": "The story of Samson appears in which book of the Old Testament?", "answer": "Judges", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a1a34a12f2a7826b9b8724", "question": "What was E.T.'s favorite candy?", "answer": "Recee's Pieces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0f", "question": "What is comedian Jon Stewart's full birth name?", "answer": "Jonathan Stuart Leibowitz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a096", "question": "Which film features the line, \"I could have been a contender\"?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b58f", "question": "What Cuban products include Montecristo, Cohiba and Romeo y Julieta?", "answer": "Cigars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c640", "question": "By what name is Sodium Chloride better known as?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4d", "question": "Who wrote the ballets \"The Sleeping Beauty\" and \"The Nutcracker\"?", "answer": "Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf4", "question": "What was the nickname of restaurateur Dave Thomas' second daughter?", "answer": "Wendy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb57de5dad637d903c880c", "question": "What is the name of the oldest bridge in Venice, which crosses the city's famous Grand Canal?", "answer": "The Ponte di Rialto, or Rialto Bridge, was built between 1588 and 1591 to span the width of the Grand Canal.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d116e14fea7fe947a22274", "question": "From what Gaelic word is \"Dublin\" derived?", "answer": "Dublind", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a1", "question": "What sailor's disease resulted from a deficiency of Vitamin C?", "answer": "Scurvy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace1", "question": "What were the first words Edison spoke into the phonograph he had just invented?", "answer": "Mary had a little lamb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beef", "question": "If a dish is served pomontier, what does it contain?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e147a6b6ca6dac04a20ca4e", "question": "When did Thomas Jefferson purchase the territory of Louisiana?", "answer": "1803", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e5", "question": "What lake was created in the 1900s when the Colorado River broke through an embankment?", "answer": "Salton Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbb", "question": "What model was married to musician Billy Joel?", "answer": "Christie Brinkley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc97", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Cesta\"?", "answer": "Jai alai", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601371ad138175489539638c", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him huge royalties: at the peak of the show's popularity, he took home $800,000 to $900,000 annually.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a700", "question": "Which US state is home to Great Sand Dunes National Monument?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5922022fa4edfd43a087addd", "question": "What is the first day of Lent called?", "answer": "Ash Wednesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339427", "question": "What character was Bela Lugosi best known for playing?", "answer": "Dracula", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc6beec223966ae8f8887", "question": "What is Neo's official name in the film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Anthony A. Anderson, which is why Agent Smith refers to him as \"Mr. Anderson\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbd", "question": "Who wrote \"Kubla Khan\"?", "answer": "Samuel Taylor Coleridge", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8de5ec223966ae8f8859", "question": "What character does Will Ferrell play in the movie \"Anchorman\"?", "answer": "Ron Burgundy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a21b12f2a7826b9b8718", "question": "What sport would you be playing if the score was deuce?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133896c", "question": "Who replaced Severus Snape as Potions Master at Hogwarts School?", "answer": "Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbee06ce05a3942286ef8", "question": "Who recorded the song \"King for a Day\"?", "answer": "Thompson Twins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febaa167e83c707845b20db", "question": "Where was the world's first public aquarium?", "answer": "London", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59bb287ac9bff04efae6d750", "question": "Who wrote the book on which the Oscar winning film \"The Godfather\" was based?", "answer": "Mario Puzo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad34", "question": "Which company developed the A6M fighter plane known as \"Zero\" during WWII?", "answer": "Mitsubishi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8e", "question": "What Beatles song repeats the title in the lyrics forty-one times?", "answer": "Let It Be", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d8", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Fighting Quaker\"?", "answer": "Smedley Butler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f55", "question": "What James Joyce story collection begins with \"The Sisters\" and ends with \"The Dead\"?", "answer": "Dubliners", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc33a6ce05a3942286f20", "question": "In the film \"Capote\", who played the role of Truman Capote's love interest?", "answer": "Bruce Greenwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb3", "question": "Violeta Chamorro was the leader of what country?", "answer": "Nicaragua", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133968d", "question": "On the TV show \u201cFriends,\u201d what was the name of Ross\u2019 pet monkey?", "answer": "Marcel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959c", "question": "Who plays the broken-hearted widower in the 2003 movie \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Liam Neeson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7d062877e98cb97778a60", "question": "Tarawa is located in what group of islands?", "answer": "The Gilbert Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92f", "question": "What yard line must a football team drive to, to reach the \"red zone\"?", "answer": "The 20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59412664bab1e6f9796f1b58", "question": "How long does a day last on Uranus?", "answer": "17 hours", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b8", "question": "The Province of Saskatchewan shares its southern border with which two US states?", "answer": "Montana and North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338986", "question": "What name is given to the overweight boy with glasses in the book \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "Piggy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7e5eff048f679a45ac0c", "question": "Bacteriophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Bacteria", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff6686852a821ff76ae8b04", "question": "Who are the first people known to have consumed chocolate?", "answer": "There is evidence that the ancient Olmecs of what is now Mexico consumed chocolate beverages as far back as 1900 BC.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc98", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Catenaccio\"?", "answer": "Soccer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2c", "question": "What novel by Lucy Maud Montgomery became Canada's longest-running main stage musical?", "answer": "Anne of Green Gables", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339485", "question": "Who stars as Walter Fielding Jr. in the 1986 movie \"The Money Pit\"?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fee", "question": "Who got his signature left-ear piercing in 1986, after interviewee Liza Minnelli encouraged him to do it?", "answer": "Ed Bradley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd55cec223966ae8f88d0", "question": "\"You\u2019re gonna need a bigger boat\" originated in what movie?", "answer": "\"Jaws\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb32665ff7d326b622a7e", "question": "Who recorded such songs as \"Toys in the Attic\" and \"Angel\", and also wrote music for the film \"Armageddon\"?", "answer": "Aerosmith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfbd49dc5ec6cd98a8318", "question": "Who painted \"The Starry Night\"?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f91", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"The Turning Point\"?", "answer": "Leslie Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b243", "question": "What king was executed for the excesses of his inquisitional \"Star Chamber\"?", "answer": "Charles I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef94596ce05a3942286e97", "question": "What was on the first-ever 12-inch record?", "answer": "Beethoven's Fifth Symphony", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a9b", "question": "On \"Cheers\", what was the name of the upscale seafood restaurant located directly above Cheers?", "answer": "Melville's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a0", "question": "Which actress played alongside Arnold Schwarzenegger in the 1990 movie \"Total Recall\"?", "answer": "Sharon Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febba227e83c707845b2143", "question": "How much was spent producing the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "An estimated $25 million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aacf", "question": "What is the second largest state in the US?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ccf7965b37b32637bdc44be", "question": "What shape is a wombat\u2019s fecal matter?", "answer": "Cubic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef92086ce05a3942286e7f", "question": "In what state did Bob Dillon grow up?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf95", "question": "Sweetbread is derived from what organ?", "answer": "Pancreas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c538fbde8045e48466a9", "question": "What four-legged animal is considered a marine mammal?", "answer": "Polar bear -- They rely on the sea to provide their main food source (mostly seals) and need sea ice platforms to hunt them.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e96b07ccba3ffe45786f0", "question": "What area in the US translates from the Dutch as \"Marshland\"?", "answer": "Brooklyn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b323532bf195a31e15d73ac", "question": "What musical instrument did Jack Benny play?", "answer": "The violin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c831", "question": "The \"Wandering\" species of what bird has the longest wingspan in nature?", "answer": "Albatross", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d15", "question": "What comic strip features a family dog named Barfy?", "answer": "The Family Circus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899c3c60d398dc9cf7a6a6", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Hestia?", "answer": "Vesta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e0", "question": "Which pasta has a calamari-like shape?", "answer": "Calamarata", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c17b877e98cb97778977", "question": "Which of the Great Lakes does not have a border with Canada?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc3296de0eb824d4052eb", "question": "Which American city is considered to be the birthplace of blues music?", "answer": "Memphis, Tennessee -- In 1977, the U.S. Congress declared Beale Street to be the official \"Home of the Blues\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cdd10e347d002c297e4ec", "question": "How was the Greek city of Troy penetrated?", "answer": "Using a wooden horse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70a", "question": "According to Irish superstition, what stands open during the 12 days of Christmas?", "answer": "The gates of heaven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133900d", "question": "What fruit was referred to as \"Golden Apple\" in Greek myth?", "answer": "Apricot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c0", "question": "What kind of store did John Travolta\u2019s character work at in the movie \"Saturday Night  Fever\"?", "answer": "Hardware store", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133badb", "question": "What card game with a Spanish name is named for the word you must yell when you get down to one card?", "answer": "Uno", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d47423f8e329de4f877899", "question": "How many litres does a Nebuchadnezzar contain?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e7", "question": "Guitarist Dave Navarro was married for just over three years to which star of \"Baywatch\" and \"Singled Out\"?", "answer": "Carmen Electra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3b", "question": "On what TV show is Momcorp the world's largest megacorporation?", "answer": "Futurama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae865ac7f28483af1e7fdd1", "question": "In 2018, a meme featured what Sonic character with a Ugandan accent saying: \"Do you know the way?\"", "answer": "Knuckles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e37", "question": "Who plays drums on the Beatles track \"Back in the U.S.S.R.\"?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b048", "question": "In what year did Lewis & Clark depart St. Louis to begin their expedition to the west?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a841", "question": "The ancient city of Troy was located in what is now what country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d5f", "question": "In Chinese mythology, what is a \"qilin\"?", "answer": "A Chinese unicorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18d", "question": "What is the name of the oscar winning actor who is the spokesperson for Farmer's Insurance?", "answer": "J.K. Simmons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396aa", "question": "What brand of beverage has its containers visible in many shots in the movie \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "Starbucks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb735e75e259d786908732a", "question": "What two men are considered the most notable two-time recepients of Congressional Medals of Honor?", "answer": "Smedley Butler and Dan Daly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989ac89cb8751d53e7d760a", "question": "When was the polka dot jersey first awarded at the Tour de France to the \"King of the Mountains\"?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab2fd0b8cce1e6fda7041", "question": "Botanophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Plants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0d", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was Crazy Craving?", "answer": "Honeycomb", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f8", "question": "What was the subtitle of the 2005 movie \"Miss Congeniality 2\"?", "answer": "Armed and Fabulous", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febba977e83c707845b2145", "question": "What was the first Super Bowl to use Roman numerals in its title?", "answer": "Super Bowl V", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b120", "question": "What historical figure appeared on the face of the US dollar coins minted from 1979 to 1981, and again in 1999?", "answer": "Susan B. Anthony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b206", "question": "On what saint's day in 1572 did Catherine de Medicis have 3,000 Protestants killed in Paris?", "answer": "St. Bartholomew's Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338876", "question": "Who does Alice follow down the hole?", "answer": " The White Rabbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf3", "question": "What two things are being compared in a stock's \"P/E ratio\"?", "answer": "Share price and earnings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe36b810ada16518afdc03b", "question": "What animal is on the label of \"Shiner Bock\" beer?", "answer": "Big-Horned Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec83eaec223966ae8f87fa", "question": "The musical group 3T are all relatives of which legendary pop musician?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2d", "question": "The Supreme Court decision that legalized abortion in the US was referred to by what case name?", "answer": "Roe vs. Wade", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c88d", "question": "What does the Holmes and Rahe scale measure?", "answer": "Stress caused by life events", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e859fe83fe1f2a824bdb", "question": "Which English king built castles in the 13th century to help conquer Wales?", "answer": "Edward I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff51ca6ff04d658268c9319", "question": "Which U.S. aircraft carrier was sunk at the Battle of Midway?", "answer": "USS Yorktown CV-5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b09f", "question": "At what theatre was Abraham Lincoln shot?", "answer": "Ford's Theatre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec7", "question": "The album \"American Beauty/American Psycho\" was released in 2015 by which American rock band?", "answer": "Fall Out Boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c617", "question": "How many chromosomes are in human DNA?", "answer": "46", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93b446bd93ce3a4e5f6a1", "question": "According to Galileo's biographer, what tower did he climb to prove his \"Law of Falling Objects\" theory?", "answer": "Tower of Pisa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa5711c73aa70ea0b70b30", "question": "Before the oil industry grew in the 1940s, what was the major industry for Qatar.", "answer": "Pearls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c415", "question": "What animal produces most of the world's wool?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d44", "question": "What year was artist Claude Monet born in?", "answer": "1840", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339228", "question": "What is \"Shawshank\" in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A prison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c512", "question": "What is the largest muscle in the human body?", "answer": "Gluteus maximus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c13", "question": "Who is the duo what created the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Trey Parker and Matt Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef8", "question": "Which two fruits are an anagram of each other?", "answer": "Lemon and melon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a6", "question": "Roadrunners are members of which family of birds?", "answer": "Cuckoos", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfba", "question": "What is a Ramekin?", "answer": "A small casserole dish\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be14", "question": "What does a DNR order at a hospital stand for?", "answer": "Do Not Resuscitate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339612", "question": "In which movie does Woody Allen awaken 200 years in the future?", "answer": "Sleeper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa55273838c5c8a417f23", "question": "Who discovered the life or death importance of washing hands while studying maternity wards?", "answer": "Ignaz Philipp Semmelweis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c701", "question": "What is the atomic number of gold?", "answer": "79", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3de2ff048f679a45ab55", "question": "What do insects take oxygen through?", "answer": "Spiracles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f5674f33a95c66dc4fe769", "question": "Who is Mega Man's creator?", "answer": "Dr. Light", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c9", "question": "What queen were the Virgin Islands named for in 1627?", "answer": "Elizabeth I", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a5530b3e1c6f9840ba31a0", "question": "Which band recorded the album \"Fly Like an Eagle\" in 1975 to 1976?", "answer": "Steve Miller Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ce47877e98cb97778a3f", "question": "What are the 3 major islands of the Philippines?", "answer": "Luzon, Visayas and Mindanao", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d6", "question": "Tommy Lee Jones and Al Gore were roommates at what university?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace6", "question": "Which country was former Prime Minister Tony Blair born in?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a780", "question": "What geographical boundary was first surveyed in 1763 by Charles and Jeremiah?", "answer": "The Mason-\u00adDixon Line", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5902a166cad1ec93f27df776", "question": "What dialect term describes rough cider made from unselected apples?", "answer": "Scrumpy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5971e08e89261e916c8e09ad", "question": "What US state was \"Steak 'n Shake\" founded in?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4a", "question": "Gangster Al Capone was eventually arrested and convicted on what charge?", "answer": "Tax evasion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6652da5bfecdd737e085c", "question": "What was the U.S. population in 1900?", "answer": "76,094,000", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f0", "question": "What city, located at the head of the Niagara River, is the seat of New York's Erie County?", "answer": "Buffalo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d0", "question": "How many rivers does Saudi Arabia have?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a743", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Old Line State\"?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008df93f4f3bc4a292f862c", "question": "What does Passover commemorate?", "answer": "It commemorates how Moses safely led the Jews out of Egypt, where they had spent centuries living in slavery under the Pharaohs.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cf", "question": "Who directed the 2007 sci-fi movie \"Sunshine\"?", "answer": "Danny Boyle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b272", "question": "What Filipino volcano's 1991 eruption produced ten times more ash than Mount Saint Helens had?", "answer": "Mount Pinatubo's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea481fff048f679a45abaf", "question": "Which medical term means vomiting?", "answer": "Emesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ade", "question": "What author's Jamaican estate was called \"Goldeneye\"?", "answer": "Ian Fleming's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe1ec33145fb29466707385", "question": "What is the primary ingredient in a \"hoecake\"?", "answer": "Cornmeal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2132b31a458464a93c44e", "question": "The red food-coloring carmine is extracted from which source?", "answer": "Crushed beetles called cochineal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca39", "question": "Which element appears fifth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Boron", "category": "science"}]